Elizabeth Olsavsky

Web Developer ● Austin, Texas ● elizabetholsavsky@gmail.com

Projects



Visit elizabetholsavsky.com to view full portfolio and project details.

Scriptly Speaking Blog

Node, mySQL, Sequelize, Express, Bcrypt, Handlebars, CSS

CMS-style blog using express-session npm package for authentication. Users have the ability to create, edit, and delete both posts and comments while logged in. Non-members have the ability to view posts and comments and are prompted to log in if they would like to leave a comment or post.

Weather Dashboard

JavaScript, Bulma, CSS, Server-Side API

Retrieves real-time and forecasted weather conditions for the user's city by accessing the Open Weather API. Previous searches are stored in local storage and can be accessed again via dynamically-generated buttons.

Fusion Fables Team Project

Node, mySQL, Sequelize, Express, Bcrypt, Handlebars, Bootstrap

Blog-style writing platform for collaborative projects where users can share ideas and contribute to others. Worked collaboratively with teammates in agile workflow using GitHub projects and kanban board. Resolved git conflicts, pair-programmed, and problem-solved to surpass our MVP. Contributed to back end and routing.



Visit github.com/elizabetholsavsky to explore source code and additional projects including: Node, JavaScript, React, Express, Sequelize, mySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, GraphQL, CSS

Education

Austin UT Boot Camps

Remote

Jan. 2023-Jul. 2023

Full Stack Web Development Certificate

Youngstown State University

Youngstown, OH

Aug. 2012-Aug. 2014

• Master of Science in Literacy • Master of Science in Curriculum & Instruction

Cleveland State University

Cleveland, OH

Aug. 2008-Dec. 2011

• Bachelor of Science in Early Childhood Education, summa cum laude

Work Experience

Classroom Educator, Del Valle ISD

Del Valle, TX

Aug. 2014-Aug. 2023

- Demonstrated expertise as Grade Level Leader and guided teammates towards achieving collective goals.
- Meticulously collected and organized student data. Analyzed data to design highly-effective differentiated instruction to meet the needs of all students. Incorporated research-based strategies from professional publications and personal research. Leveraged innovative digital resources and tools to create dynamic and interactive lessons as a Google Certified Educator.
- Mentored several new teachers and provided support and guidance to foster professional growth.

Graduate Assistant, YSU

Youngstown, OH

Aug. 2012-Aug. 2014

- Organized the university's first educational technology conference in Summer 2014 by locating, contacting, and communicating with education technology vendors. Also organized the Fall 2012 literacy conference.
- Researched and presented "Promoting Positive, Collaborative, and Insightful Partnerships Between the University Supervisor, Teacher Candidate and Classroom Teacher" with Dr. Ratican at statewide conference.